In order to further understand that
though, we do first have to understand
the event object a little more. So, what
I'm going to do is I'm going to get rid
of this log here, and I'll put it back
for the next video. Um, but we're just
going to have this log here. If we want
to see the event, we can actually pass
it as a we can actually pass it into our
function. Here in our function, we need
to accept it. Um, oftent times when
you're accepting an event, it's
abbreviated as E. You can type out event
because again you can name your
parameter whatever you want but it'll
receive whatever gets passed in. So I'm
going to call mine e and I'm just going
to log out
console.log
e.
So if we come over to our running page
and we click on this innermost layer.
Remember technically when we click on
this we're clicking on the one in front
of it and the one outside of there. So,
if we click, we get a pointer event and
we can actually open this up and it's an
object and
it has a lot of attributes. One of the
attributes that's really interesting is
it's a type. It says the event that just
happened was a click event. Um, the
other thing that's helpful is it has a
target and that target is this div with
the class of third. So, this div right
here, you can see it highlighted and if
I click on it, it actually takes me over
to the HTML page and highlights it. So
you can see exactly which
which thing was targeted.
Um we can see the pointer type is mouse.
Um
we can see there's just a whole bunch of
details here. Um
and so you can see a whole bunch of
things about the event. Two things that
are really helpful to know about the
event. One of those is to know the
event.target because then you know what
got clicked and I'm going to console.log
um the item that was clicked was and
then I'm going to log out the target and
then I'm going to say console.log log
the item that
has the event
handler is and then below it I'm going
to log console.log
ecurrent
target.
So we're going to save this and we're
going to come over. If I click here it
says the item that was clicked was div
class third two layers in. So we can see
that it's that div. The item that has
the event handler is this big outer
object. So we clicked here, it bubbled
up and then it triggered the log here.
So
current item, sorry. So current target
is the one that actually has the event,
the onclick event. Target is where the
click actually happened. So if you want
to know what they actually clicked on,
then you use target. If you want to know
which event handler got called, then you
use current target and that'll tell you
the HTML element that handles that
event.
But let's come back here and we're going
to add back those on click events.
And I will show you in the next video
how to prevent the bubbling that we just
saw.